Mss.Rec.1 Mss.Rec.1
American Philosophical Society
- Series 2, Mss.Rec.1.2
  - Death Song, 1948; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - The Coward's Song, 1948-05-05; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
  - Love Song, 1948; 17-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "Joe Chingwa's own composition in traditional Ottawa style."
    Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Love songs; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - Love Song, 1948; 17-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:17; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "ciigobei dibik', 'All night, etc.' Traditional Ottawa love song supposed to be sung by a man."
  - Wedding Dance Song, 1948; 17-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:27; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music; Weddings--Songs and music
  - Courtship Dance Song, 1948; 17-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:40; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    Courtship--Songs and music; Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - Ghost Dance Song, 1948; 17-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:44; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "Ndássanawes--'I am playing, etc.' A social dance."
    Ghost dance; Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - Medicine Chant, 1948; 17-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:39; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "Šaškòbinnéši webagamáganiya, 'Bluebird ?'. Joe Chingwa learned this chant from his grandfather, Mkkw niwi, who obtained the chant in a vision. Meaning not known, but it refers to herbs."
    Herbs; Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - Challenge Song, 1948; 17-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:34; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "Kagowi anigassasi, 'I am not afraid of anyone.' This is the same wording as ['War Chant' (APSdigrec_0589)] but omits meaningless chant and tune and rhythm vary."
  - Ottawa Pipe Dance, 1948; 17-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
  - Gambling Song, 1948; 17-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:43; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    Traditional Ottawa gambling song sung during counter gambling game.
    Gambling--Songs and music; Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - Eagle Dance Song, 1948; 17-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:35; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "(Nimigoni'mag', etc. 'My feathers, etc.') Traditional Ottawa eagle dance song."
    Eagle dance; Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa dance; Ottawa Indians--Music
  - Social Dance Song, 1948; 17-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
  - War Chant, 1948; 17-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:43; Chingwa, Joe; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    "(Kágowi etc., 'No one etc.') Traditional Ottawa war chang sung before a battle. The wording is that same as ['Challenge Song' (APSdigrec_0584)] except that on the latter the tune and rhythm are slightly different and a meaningless chant preceeding the song are omitted."
  - Adoption, 1947; 17-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:25; Ettawageshik, Fred, 1896-1969; Ettawageshik, Jane, 1915-1996
    Indians of North America--Michigan--Music; Michigan; Ottawa Indians--Music